Hugo Day

Nationality: British Personal DETAILS Full UK Driver's License Contact Avenue du Jura, 49

mobile: +44 7890 945140 Ferney-Voltaire, 01210, France e-mail: hugoaday@gmail.com ch.linkedin.com/pub/hugo-day/31/500/528/ https://github.com/Tontonis

Professional STATEMENT

Information

I am an applied physicist with extensive experience working in technically challenging, international environments, mostly in an academic or humanitarian setting. 5+ years experience working with particle accelerators, with an emphasis on electromagnetics and RF engineering. I'm active in the hacker community and am committed to continued professional development and outreach/education

in STEM subjects.

Problem solving, experimental work/design, data analysis, RF engineering, complex systems, numer-Proficiencies ical methods, technical design and presentation

Computing SKILLS

HFSS, CST: Microwave Studio, pSpice, Cadence, C, C++, Matlab, Mathematica, Python, SciPy, Matplotlib, Java, I⁴TFX 2€, R, Git, *nix and Windows administration, openoffice and MS Office

Professional EXPERIENCE

CERN, Geneva, Switzerland

Senior Research Fellow

July 2013 - June 2016

Worked in the fast pulsed systems group of the technology department on various topics related to the LHC injection kicker magnets, focused on electromagnetic interactions between the particle beam and the electromagnet. Worked extensively with standard EM software (HFSS, CST:MWS, pSpice, Cadence) and bench RF test stands (VNAs).

- Proposed an upgrade to EM performance of magnet which was subsequently applied to all kicker magnets during 2013 maintenance shutdown
- Lead study of HV behaviour of cathode triple junction as applied to LHC kicker magnet geometry
- Implemented an library of analysis tools for measurements and simulations in python for transparency and reuse

CERN, Geneva, Switzerland

Doctoral Student

February 2010 – January 2013

Examining the electromagnetic interactions between charged particle beams and particle accelerator components using simulation suites and bench-top measurements techniques. Focused on normalconducting fast pulsed electromagnets and collimators (robust beam protection equipment) necessitating dealing with competing design requirements to find optimal solutions.

- Lead simulation and measurement campaign of beam coupling impedance of the LHC injection magnets, collaborating with colleagues in other departments at CERN and in other research institutes in the UK and Germany
- Devised an analysis technique to measure beam impedance in asymmetric structures
- Carried out a systematic review of impedance reduction techniques, their advantages/disadvantages and implementation

University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom

Teaching Assistant

September 2010 – January 2011

Teaching assistant for undergraduate courses (Programming in C).

EDUCATION

University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom

Doctor of Philosophy

September 2009 – June 2013

- Thesis title: "Measurements and Simulations of Impedance Reduction Techniques in Particle Accelerators" supervised by Professor Roger Jones and Dr Elias Metral (CERN)- Work done under placement at CERN.
- I used theoretical models, commercial EM modelling software (CST Microwave Studio and Ansoft HFSS) and bench top RF measurements to evaluate and characterise the EM properties of accelerator components. Working in an internationally diverse team, results were regularly presented internally for review and feedback, with communication between operational and design teams to integrate the RF results into their design revisions.

University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom

MPhys (Hons) Physics Classification: 1st Class

October 2005 - July 2009

- Masters' Thesis: "Controlling the synthesis of branched gold nanoparticles using a wet chemical synthesis method" resulting in a journal publication under the supervision of Dr. Antonios Kanaras
- Courses in experimental design, classical and quantum physics, mathematics, general relativity and fluid dynamics

King Edward VI Grammas School, Chelmsford, United Kingdom

A Levels Physics, Mathematics, Chemistry, History

2000 - 2005

PROJECTS

CosmicPi

Software and Physics Analysis

https://www.cosmicpi.org June 2014 - Present

- Building an low-cost, open source, distributed cosmic ray detector
- Taking lead on physics capabilities and analysis tools. Adapting data for use with HiSPARC's Sapphire framework

OpenCosmics

https://github.com/OpenCosmics/opencosmics.github.io

- Providing a framework to allow interoperable analysis of different cosmic ray experiments' data
- Building on HiSPARC's Sapphire framework, we're working to import different data sources in a functional manner

Volunteer EXPERIENCE

THE Port, Geneva, Switzerland

Fundraising, Event Organisation, Team Mentor

June 2014 - Present

- Organisation of a humanitarian hackathon in coordination with Red Cross, UN and other bodies
- Assisted in fundraising, recruiting volunteers for event and mentoring participants

CERN, Geneva, Switzerland

CERN Tour Guide/Conferencier

November 2010 - June 2016

- Tour guide to audience from secondary school students to visiting dignitaries
- Gave introductory talks about CERN and it's mission and tours to experimental areas

Pint of Science CH, Geneva, United Kingdom

Geneva Coordinator

October 2013 - May 2014

- Managed a city wide public science event serving over 250 members of the public in 2 pubs over 2 nights
- Recruited and coordinated venue managers, and liased with national organising committee

LHComedy/Comedy Collider, Geneve, United Kingdom

Advertisement/Performer

July 2013 - June 2014

- Responsible for advertising and marketing
- Stand up comedy events taking place at CERN in September 2013 and June 2014. starring professional physicists giving amateur stand up comedy sets alongside professional comedians to the general public in a sold out 200 seat capacity venue

Publications

Day, H.A., Bartczak, D., Fairbairn, N., McGuire, E., Ardakan, M., Porter, A. E. and Kanaras, A.G., "Controlling the three-dimensional morphology of nanocrystals", CrystEngComm, 2010, 12, 4312-4316.

Conference Publications

- Day, H.A., Barnes, M., Ducimetire, L. Vega Cid, L., Weterings, W. "Current and Future Beam Thermal Behaviour of the LHC Injection Kicker Magnet", THPMW031, IPAC'16, Busan, Korea, 2016.
- Barnes, M.J., Adraktas, A., Bregliozzi, G., Calatroni, S., Day, H., Ducimetire, L., Goddard, B., Gomes Namora, V., Mertens, V., Salvant, B., Uythoven, J, Vega Cid, L., Weterings, W., Yin Vallgren, C. . "Operational Experience of the Upgraded LHC Injection Kicker Magnets", THPMW033, IPAC'16, Busan, Korea, 2016.
- Barnes, M.J., Adraktas, A., Beck, M., Bregliozzi, G., Day, H., Ducimetire, L., Ferreira Somoza, J.A., Goddard, B., Krame, T., Pasquino, C., Rumolo, G., Salvant, B., Uythoven, J, Sermus, L. Vega Cid, L., Velotti, F., Weterings, W., Zannini, C. Yin Vallgren, C. . "Studies of Impedance-related Improvements of the SPS Injection Kickers", THPMW033, IPAC'16, Busan, Korea, 2016.
- Adraktas, A., Barnes, M.J., Day, H., Ducimetire, L. Yin Vallgren, C. . "High Voltage Performance of Surface Coatings on Alumina Insulators", THPMW028, IPAC'16, Busan, Korea, 2016.
- B. Salvant, O. Aberle, M. Albert, R. Alemany-Fernandez, G. Arduini, J. Baechler, M.J. Barnes, P. Baudrenghien, O. E. Berrig, N. Biancacci, G. Bregliozzi, F. Carra, F. Caspers, P. Chiggiato, A. Danisi, H.A. Day, M. Deile, D. Druzhkin, S. Jakobsen, J. Kuczerowski, A. Lechner, R. Losito, A. Masi, E. Mtral, N. Minafra, A. Nosych, A. Perillo Marcone, D. Perini, S. Redaelli, F. Roncarolo, G. Rumolo, E. Shaposhnikova, J. Uythoven, A. J. Vlimaa, J. E. Varela Campelo, C. Vollinger, M. Wendt, J. Wenninger, C. Zannini, J.F. Esteban Muller. "Beam Induced RF Heating in the LHC in 2015", MOPOR008, IPAC'16, Busan, Korea, 2016.
- C. Belver-Aguilar, A. Faus-Golfe, F. Toral, M.J. Barnes, H. Day "Transverse Impedance Measurements and DC Breakdown Tests on the First Stripline Kicker Prototype for the CLIC Damping Ring", MOPOR008, IPAC'15, Richmond, USA, 2015.
- H. Day, M.J. Barnes, L. Coralejo Feliciano "Impedance Studies of the LHC Injection Kicker Magnets for HL-LHC", MOPJE038, IPAC'15, Richmond, USA, 2015.
- H. Day, M.J. Barnes, F. Caspers, E. Mtral, B. Salvant "Beam Coupling Impedance of the New Beam Screen of the LHC Injection Kicker Magnets", TUPRI030, IPAC'14, Dresden, Germany, 2014.
- M.J. Barnes, P. Adraktas, G. Bregliozzi, S. Calatroni, P. Costa-Pinta, H. Day, L. Ducimetire, T. Kramer, V. Namora, V. Mertens, M. Taborelli "High Voltage Performance of the Beam Screen of the LHC Injection Kicker Magnets", MOPME074, IPAC'14, Dresden, Germany, 2014.
- C. Belver-Aguilar, A. Faus-Golfe, F. Toral, M.J. Barnes, H. Day "Measurements and Laboratory Tests on a Prototype Stripline Kicker for the CLIC Damping Rings", MOPRO027, IPAC'14, Dresden, Germany, 2014.
- H. Day, M.J. Barnes, F. Caspers, E. Mtral, B. Salvant "Evalutation of the Beam Coupling Impedance of the New Beam Screen Designs for the LHC Injection Kickers", TUPME033, IPAC'13, Shanghai, China, 2013.
- Day, H.A., Barnes, M., Caspers, F., Jones, R.M., Metral, E., Salvant, B. "Evaluation of the Beam Coupling Impedance of New Beam Screen Designs for the LHC Injection Kicker Magnets", WEPPR071, IPAC'12, New Orleans, US, 2012.
- Day, H.A., Caspers, F., Dallocchio, A., Gentini, L., Grudiev, A., Jones, R.M., Metral, E., Salvant, B. "Beam Coupling Impedance of the LHC TCTP Collimators", WEPPR070, IPAC'12, New Orleans, US, 2012.
- Day, H.A., Caspers, F., Jones, R.M., Metral, E. "Simulations of Coaxial Wire Measurements of the Impedance of Asymmetric Structures.", MOPS079, IPAC'11, San Sebastian, Spain, 2011.
- Day, H.A., Barnes, M., Caspers, F., Jones, R.M., Metral, E., Salvant, B., C. Zannini "Coaxial Wire Measurements of Ferrite Kicker Magnets", MOPS078, IPAC'11, San Sebastian, Spain, 2011.
- Day, H.A., Caspers, F., Jones, R.M., Metral, E., Salvant, B. "Comparison of the current LHC Collimators and the SLAC Phase 2 Collimator Impedances", MOPS080, IPAC'11, San Sebastian, Spain, 2011.

INVITED TALKS

- Day, H.A., Biancacci, N., Salvant, B. Zannini, C. "Impedance simulations of the LHC collimators and low beta simulations of ferrite kicker magnets with CST Particle Studio", 6th CST European User Group Meeting, Freising, Germany, 2011.
- Day, H.A. "Impedance Reductin Techniques: LHC Collimators and Injection Kicker Magnets", ICFA Mini-Workshop on Electromagnetic Wakefields and Impedances in Particle Accelerators, Erice, Italy, 2014.

Day, H.A., Barnes, M.J.. "Surface Flashover in Fast Pulsed Kicker Systems", 5th International Workshop on Mechanisms of Vacuum Arcs, Saariselka, Finland, 2015.

Languages English (Fluent), French (Professional Proficiency), German (Beginner)

Geneve 23, Switzerland, CH-1211 Geneve 23, Switzerland, CH-1211 phone: available on request e-mail: mike.barnes@cern.ch e-mail: elias.metral@cern.ch